<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Sense of Openness (Posts about Open Source)</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/categories/cat_open-source.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:belkinsa@ubuntu.com"&gt;Svetlana Belkin&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 23:24:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Back to Ubuntu Touch!</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/back-to-ubuntu-touch/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, I thought about buying a new phone and the thought process was this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phone must be/have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A non-Samsung or iPhone&lt;/strong&gt; While they are best of the best, they are just over advertised. Plus, they cost above my pay rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy, please&lt;/strong&gt; It's something that we have, as a whole, thrown away. Also, that FaceTime bug is scary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It needs to be simple&lt;/strong&gt; I'm still leaning on using my computer for my work. I only use my phone to make calls, text, and check my e-mail and Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It needs to be rootable&lt;/strong&gt; What if I want to switch back to Android? Plus, how would I of switched to Ubuntu Touch in the first place? If I were to switch back to Android, I would use the stock ROM- no need for bloat-ware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to buy a Nexus 5 and put Ubuntu Touch on it. I used to have a Nexus 4, but it was water damaged. I bought it because I wanted a bigger screen although I think based on the usage, the Nexus 4 would of worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't recall if I wrote a proper review on Ubuntu Touch, but I will here. Like as I said I don't really use my phone and I will not be reviewing the convergence part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation was much easier after &lt;a href="https://ubports.com/"&gt;Ubports&lt;/a&gt; took over the project because they added a GUI method to flashing Ubuntu Touch on devices. The the only problem that I found is that Nexus 5 wasn't found automatically. Luckily, the installer has a manual selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/SwitchingUbuntuTouch/UbportsMainScreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/SwitchingUbuntuTouch/UbportsSuccessScreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it's a nice and stable system. I don't see any major changes from when I last used it. The one thing that I love is the fact you can respond to messages from the indicator menu. The only bad thing is that the Weather app doesn't work outside the box. You will have to update it from the Ubuntu Open Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apps I have on my Ubuntu Touch are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Base, pre-installed apps minus Notes&lt;/strong&gt; I don't use Evernote but I may need a basic noting taking app. The others are needed for everyday life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/activescreen.mivoligo"&gt;Active Screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It replaces the "always on while charging" setting from Android. I may have use for it, but I don't yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/circle-message.mivoligo"&gt;Circle Message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It's there for motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morph Browser&lt;/strong&gt; While it's one of the base, pre-installed apps, it the most powerful app on the Ubuntu Touch. Most of the apps that I used on my Samsung Galaxy Edge are web-based apps, such as Twitter and e-mail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/talaan.kugiigi"&gt;Talaan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It's a pretty good check-list app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/ut-tweak-tool.sverzegnassi"&gt;UT Tweak Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Because there are some settings that aren't found the system settings, such as turning off the launcher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lockscreen looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/SwitchingUbuntuTouch/HomeScreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/back-to-ubuntu-touch/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 18:33:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ubuntu 18.04 LTS Review</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/ubuntu-1804-lts-review/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resisting change can be a blessing and a cruse and resisting changing to Ubuntu 18.04 LTS is a cruse. While I'm sad that I leaving Unity behind, due to some issues on 16.04 LTS, I'm glad that I decided to switch. Though I do miss Unity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to do a minimal install instead of a full one because there are many programs that I do need.  I only need Firefox, PDF Reader,video player, and the core system programs. The rest of the programs that I need, including ReText and the System76 drivers, aren't included in the full install. Over the last years, I noticed that I don't use LibreOffice or the music player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal installation option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar apps such as GNOME Calendar and Evolution are better integrated with the top panel. Though it would be cool to see To Do tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReText is not integrated in the dock, it opens another instance on the dock, if favored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nautilus doesn't have the integrated bookmarked folders in the dock when right clicked on the icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No recent files on the Dash of the dock (can't think of the term)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/neofetch.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/desktop.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/ubuntu-1804-lts-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 21:53:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ReText Review</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/retext-review/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in the &lt;a href="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/posts/why-plaintext/"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I found a great Markdown editor called &lt;a href="https://github.com/ReText-project/ReText"&gt;ReText&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to write a review on the program, but for that, I wanted to show what preferences I have on.  I'm not sure if those would effect the review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/reTextPreferencesB.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/reTextPreferencesE.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/reTextPreferencesI.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ratings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;UX&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm giving UX a 7.5/10. Reason number one is there is no find/find-replace button on the tool bar. The next reason is there is no way to customize the tool bar. The third reason is the line counter hides the text when text is in that corner of the screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/LineNumberHidingText.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but it fades out when cursor is on it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/FadeWhenCursorOnIt.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is the symbols need to be defined; I don't really use symbols and some of those, such as &amp;amp; larr ; (without spaces); I don't know. I  Last but not least, the images don't show up on the live previewer. I have to use &lt;a href="http://markdownlivepreview.com/"&gt;Markdown Preview&lt;/a&gt;, a web-based tool to check the images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/ImagesDontShow.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Performance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm giving performance a 10/10 because it only uses less than 100 MiB of memory and I had no big issues with it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Features&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm giving features a 10/10 because as you can see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can export in HTML, ODT, and PDF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can have multiple documents open in tabs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can view other plaintext files&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fullscreen works in the latest version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ReText-project/reTextReview/wiki/Table-editing-mode"&gt;Table editing/formating&lt;/a&gt; is much easier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has auto-fill for numbered and un-numbered lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a live previewer and a normal one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can show where the white spaces are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can show what line you are on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows you to move lines up or down with a click of a button or a keyboard shortcut&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can show what line number you are on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can auto-save documents and auto-open last documents on start-up with window geometry from the last session&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows reStructuredText editing with previewer along with the default Markdown editing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a spell-checker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a HTML code viewer of the document that is opened&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can show what directory the file is sitting in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can insert certain symbols in text, for example: ←&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has &lt;a href="https://github.com/ReText-project/reTextReview/wiki"&gt;other features&lt;/a&gt; that are cool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I'm giving ReText a 9/10 because the features and the performance wins out over the UX.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/retext-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 15:19:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Plain Text?</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/why-plaintext/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I saw a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jrgifford/status/968136838706810882"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; about plain text productivity and like what James Gifford said, it is a "really interesting idea". This tweet stuck out me not for the productivity side of things but in terms of workflow. I ditched hierarchical note taking programs (KeepNote and Cherry Tree as examples) because I noticed that I never really used them and I was over complicating things. But the one thing that stayed with me is the use of Plain Text, A.K.A writing in Markdown. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be used everywhere- only need a text editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can still have formating via markup languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small file size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy and pasting is easier because the formating is lost in Plain Text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these pros win over the two cons that I can name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can't really do the classic outline formating.  The closest that I have is this (with spaces between the lines):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Header 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ordered Item 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Tab or four (4) lines) Unordered Item 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/OutlineinMarkdown.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline system allows you to write content without using classic outlining formating if you want to write longer items for each points without making it hard to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for a previewer for markup languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I found a Markdown editor/live previewer called &lt;a href="https://github.com/ReText-project/ReText"&gt;ReText&lt;/a&gt; which, to me, is better than GitHub's Atom or QOwnNotes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason, over Atom, is ReText dedicated for Markdown but you can still open other plain text files.  Atom is also really meant for developers. Over QOwnNotes, ReText is not a hierarchical note taking program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I draft in Markdown in ReText:
&lt;img src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/DraftingMarkdown.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that working in the Open is allowing me to think in different ways of how to do thing and this is one example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT TO ADD:&lt;/strong&gt; I forgot to talk about  that Plain Text formats don't change over versions of programs and the formats are mostly Open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/why-plaintext/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 18:46:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Nikola</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/why-nikola/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I stated previously, I switched from WordPress to Nikola for hosting my blog. Here, I want to explain more in depth on why Nikola is, to me, the best choice for a static generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Over WordPress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over that year when my blog was down, I think WordPress made some changes with their WordPress importer and I wasn't able to import from my backup file that I had. That's one reason there. I can list the other reasons along with the &lt;a href="https://getnikola.com/features/index.html"&gt;reasons&lt;/a&gt; stated on the Nikola's official site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a built-in way to write in Markdown and have it phrased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A text editor of your own choice is used. Some times that is better than the web based editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The files are stored locally and on a server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub/GitHub Pages/GitLab can be used to host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The themes are better becuase they don't have the side bar on the left-hand side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Over Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also considered using Jekyll, but I found it harder to use as a first time user of Jekyll and also for static site generators. Also &lt;strong&gt;(I think)&lt;/strong&gt;, your file formats for posts must be in a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/why-nikola/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 19:51:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>