<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Sense of Openness (Posts about life)</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/categories/life.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:belkinsa@ubuntu.com"&gt;Svetlana Belkin&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 01:15:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Blast in the Past 2</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/blast-in-the-past-2/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in September of 2013, I wrote a &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20180226181935/https://torzukarr.wordpress.com/2013/09/08/blast-in-the-past/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about who I was back in the 2000's. The other day, I was thinking about what I was doing 15 years ago which took me back to 2005 and based on that post, that was during being on deviantArt (dA), Neopets, Furcadia and my Sonic the Hedgehog, Pokemon and Megaman EXE fandom period. This was also a year before I built my first custom computer with my dad and getting my first drawing tablet. I'm not trying to summarize that post or shameless plugging it for you all to read. Instead I want to do a response to it because I clearly feel that there are places where I didn't explain myself well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forgot to add:&lt;/strong&gt; The game Puzzle Pirates by ThreeRings Design taught me to type in proper English around 2005-2006 after I build my computer.  I was just standing in (I think) the Dragon’s Nest’s Inn and watching how players were speaking.  And one caught my eye and I started to copy of that player.  The only thing is I can’t find any examples of my improper English.  I think that was on Furcadia when I was on it before 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote is half true. i may of had improper english (as an example), but it only showed when I played MMOPRG's. What I had, like most kids, was inmaturarty (&lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20040414185315/http://neosvetlana.deviantart.com:80/"&gt;example 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20060418010901/http://neosvetlana.deviantart.com:80/"&gt;example 2&lt;/a&gt; mainly the journal entires and the Devious Information). I also copied how other deviants did their journal entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on what I was doing back in the 2000's, it seemed that I wanted to create Online content. Which did translate into the 2010 decade. The proof is in this quote, "I think I also wanted to write stories and comics for the online Neopets newspaper". What I didn't really do was to follow through, but I can't really blame myself- I was a kid and I didn't care about the lore of Neopets. Which is a shame because I could of learned how to write fan-fiction, which could of lead to fiction writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless on what I could of done, what I did back than shaped me into who I am now. After building Neopets pet pages and creating blogs/sites, that made want to own a domain from very early on. Which I finally have. But I don't know how much of the 2000's me is left. The only thing that I know is that my drawing/painting style hasn't changed and the will to content creation is still strong, maybe stronger than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>life</category><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/blast-in-the-past-2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:28:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>