<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Sense of Openness (Posts about Rocket League)</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/categories/rocket-league.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:belkinsa@ubuntu.com"&gt;Svetlana Belkin&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 17:24:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>RLCS 5 Season = Mehest Season</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/rlcs-5-season-mehest-season/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I said that I'm a fan of watching Rocket League as a E-Sport and I watched most of the Rocket League Championship Series (RLCS) from the LAN of Season 2 to (as the time of writing) the regionals of Season 5. At the beginning of Season 3, I was hyped to watch each week and that stayed until Week 3 of Season 5. Season 5 was just the mehest season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm aware that I do phase out of things pretty quickly and I think this is one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reasons Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No RLCS Overtime Show&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching the VOD of RLCS Overtime because I liked hearing the casters' afterthoughts on the matches of the past weekend since I don't follow Rocket League news outside RLCS. I don't know why they didn't decide to do it this season perhaps it's because they have a new studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karma being the only female pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rocket League like all other E-sports are male dominated but there are at least one female pro. The one that I can name is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KarmahTV"&gt;Karma&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://splyce.gg/"&gt;Splyce&lt;/a&gt;. She grinded since (I think) Season 2 and she and her teammates finally made it to the Rival Series. After the play-ins, they only won two of their seven games. I feel like the pressure on Karma being the only female pro in the season. Or maybe the other teams got stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same players/teams every season&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, I do enjoy watching players being amazing or their growth but the problem is when they weaken it hurts to watch them play and lose. Plus I like seeing new rookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Player Rewards (sorry for the lack of the right word) for top in stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just a casual watcher and I don't keep track of stats or follow someone who does. Because of this, I lose track of stats and who is in the lead for certain stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Team Stats during the five minute break between matches on game day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again for the same reason as above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of the Top 5's were poorly picked&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor reason but this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dL59TL9r9rs"&gt;video's&lt;/a&gt; comments explains why. This tweet is the biggest reason on why I included this reason:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KarmahTV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@KarmahTV&lt;/a&gt;  Is this true? I saw this a comment on this video, "They had to put Karma's shot in there otherwise therd be triggered femenists" (VSME). And is this effecting your gameplay? &lt;a href="https://t.co/Xss8kDKYlc"&gt;https://t.co/Xss8kDKYlc&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YouTube?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Svetlana Belkin (@senseopenness) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/senseopenness/status/983638874613313537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasons are too short&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other E-Sports championships are much longer than five weeks of league play and a LAN. For some reason, this season went by really fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully next season is better.  Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Off-topic</category><category>Rocket League</category><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/rlcs-5-season-mehest-season/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>