<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Sense of Openness (Posts about Ubuntu)</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/categories/ubuntu.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:belkinsa@ubuntu.com"&gt;Svetlana Belkin&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 17:24:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Back to Ubuntu Touch!</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/back-to-ubuntu-touch/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, I thought about buying a new phone and the thought process was this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phone must be/have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A non-Samsung or iPhone&lt;/strong&gt; While they are best of the best, they are just over advertised. Plus, they cost above my pay rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy, please&lt;/strong&gt; It's something that we have, as a whole, thrown away. Also, that FaceTime bug is scary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It needs to be simple&lt;/strong&gt; I'm still leaning on using my computer for my work. I only use my phone to make calls, text, and check my e-mail and Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It needs to be rootable&lt;/strong&gt; What if I want to switch back to Android? Plus, how would I of switched to Ubuntu Touch in the first place? If I were to switch back to Android, I would use the stock ROM- no need for bloat-ware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to buy a Nexus 5 and put Ubuntu Touch on it. I used to have a Nexus 4, but it was water damaged. I bought it because I wanted a bigger screen although I think based on the usage, the Nexus 4 would of worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't recall if I wrote a proper review on Ubuntu Touch, but I will here. Like as I said I don't really use my phone and I will not be reviewing the convergence part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation was much easier after &lt;a href="https://ubports.com/"&gt;Ubports&lt;/a&gt; took over the project because they added a GUI method to flashing Ubuntu Touch on devices. The the only problem that I found is that Nexus 5 wasn't found automatically. Luckily, the installer has a manual selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/SwitchingUbuntuTouch/UbportsMainScreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/SwitchingUbuntuTouch/UbportsSuccessScreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it's a nice and stable system. I don't see any major changes from when I last used it. The one thing that I love is the fact you can respond to messages from the indicator menu. The only bad thing is that the Weather app doesn't work outside the box. You will have to update it from the Ubuntu Open Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apps I have on my Ubuntu Touch are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Base, pre-installed apps minus Notes&lt;/strong&gt; I don't use Evernote but I may need a basic noting taking app. The others are needed for everyday life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/activescreen.mivoligo"&gt;Active Screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It replaces the "always on while charging" setting from Android. I may have use for it, but I don't yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/circle-message.mivoligo"&gt;Circle Message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It's there for motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morph Browser&lt;/strong&gt; While it's one of the base, pre-installed apps, it the most powerful app on the Ubuntu Touch. Most of the apps that I used on my Samsung Galaxy Edge are web-based apps, such as Twitter and e-mail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/talaan.kugiigi"&gt;Talaan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It's a pretty good check-list app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://open-store.io/app/ut-tweak-tool.sverzegnassi"&gt;UT Tweak Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Because there are some settings that aren't found the system settings, such as turning off the launcher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lockscreen looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/SwitchingUbuntuTouch/HomeScreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Review</category><category>Ubuntu</category><category>Ubuntu Touch</category><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/back-to-ubuntu-touch/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 18:33:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Media PC</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/media-pc/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I forgotten that, in my house, I have big screen TVs and an unused ThinkCentre- and what prefect use for those two things? &lt;strong&gt;Watching Twitch/YouTube/Movies on the big screen!&lt;/strong&gt; A week ago, I set up my ThinkCentre media PC and I found that it's a nice set up for Ubuntu Linux. It could be better because the DisplayPort connection doesn't stay stable if the computer is left on. It will go back to the computer's speakers after awhile. The only solution at this time is to restart the computer. I also found out that there are no senors on the ThinkCentre but if you watch from a distance and/or with load volumes, you will not hear the fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current set (below) up is the TV hooked up with a full HDMI cable that goes to a switcher. I have this because I also have a Nintendo Switch hooked up to the TV by it's own full HDMI cable in the one of the ports of the switcher. In the other port, a HDMI/DisplayPort connects the ThinkCentre. A powerline adapter provides internet since the computer doesn't have a wireless network card and a Logitech media keyboard. The Ubuntu installation is a minimal 18.04 LTS installation with no extra programs expect I transferred my Firefox settings from my laptop and changed the homepage to Twitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/mediaPC/20181230_133515.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/mediaPC/20190101_142202.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I will have fun watching things on the big screen, which I haven't done forever!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Off-topic</category><category>Ubuntu</category><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/media-pc/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 17:19:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ubuntu 18.04 LTS Review</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/ubuntu-1804-lts-review/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resisting change can be a blessing and a cruse and resisting changing to Ubuntu 18.04 LTS is a cruse. While I'm sad that I leaving Unity behind, due to some issues on 16.04 LTS, I'm glad that I decided to switch. Though I do miss Unity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to do a minimal install instead of a full one because there are many programs that I do need.  I only need Firefox, PDF Reader,video player, and the core system programs. The rest of the programs that I need, including ReText and the System76 drivers, aren't included in the full install. Over the last years, I noticed that I don't use LibreOffice or the music player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal installation option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar apps such as GNOME Calendar and Evolution are better integrated with the top panel. Though it would be cool to see To Do tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReText is not integrated in the dock, it opens another instance on the dock, if favored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nautilus doesn't have the integrated bookmarked folders in the dock when right clicked on the icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No recent files on the Dash of the dock (can't think of the term)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/neofetch.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/images/desktop.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Review</category><category>Ubuntu</category><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/ubuntu-1804-lts-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 21:53:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>And We Are Back...</title><link>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/and-we-are-back/</link><dc:creator>Svetlana Belkin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;... &lt;strong&gt;FOR GOOD! And with major changes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Changed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After almost a year and two or three months, I finally got my blog running again and not with WordPress. Wordpress and JetPack/VaultPress plug-ins gave me enough headaches mainly from restoring a backup from another server/host to a new server/host. Lucky nothing was lost, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20161030014830/http://senseopenness.com:80/"&gt;content&lt;/a&gt; (thank you Internet Archive!) or money (I was able to get a full refund for both JetPack and Simple Hosting by Gandi, which I switched to).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a &lt;a href="https://bryanquigley.com/posts/converting/now-powered-by-gitlab-nikola-and-cloudflare.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by Bryan Quigley about a static site generator called &lt;a href="https://getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;. Along with the reasons on why Bryan Quigley picked to use Nikola minus the WordPress import, the two main reasons why I picked Nikola is the ability to write posts/pages in Markdown and in my favorite text editor (gedit) and the ease of first time start-up and use. I decided to not use GitLabs though or Cloudflare. If you want to try Nikola on Ubuntu, Martin Wimpress wrote a &lt;a href="https://flexion.org/posts/2015-11-installing-nikola-on-ubuntu/"&gt;great guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have tweaks to make to the blog/site but I wanted to share the news with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that much happened over the down time, but I do have some updates to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Grailvillie Wetlands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data collection season ended a month ago and, like always, I'm working on researching possible solutions- but this time for the Clermont Park Distinct (still under Grailville) since the Grail sold the north side of Grailville to them.  I have another season to data collect because it's a two year proccess for the transfer. Sad news, but at least I have a say in what they can do with the ponds. At least the land is going to good hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the lack of free time that I had, I stepped down from the CC. Mainly because I was missing the meetings because of my work schedule. There is another reason but it's something that I don't wish to share publicly at this moment in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week before the recent Ubuntu release, I tried that said release and disliked it. The reason is simple, I may be resisting change. At least I wasn't the only one who disliked it. These people use a &lt;a href="https://community.ubuntu.com/c/desktop/ubuntu-unity-dev"&gt;sub-forum&lt;/a&gt; on the community.ubuntu.com site for discussions. I invite those who want Unity 7 to maintained to join. There is also a &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~unity7maintainers"&gt;Launchpad team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to share two articles on this topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2017/11/ubuntu-unity-remix"&gt;Miss Unity? An ‘Ubuntu Unity Remix’ Could Be on the Way…&lt;/a&gt; via OMG! Ubuntu!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fossmint.com/fans-of-unity-desktop-are-working-on-a-new-remix/"&gt;Fans of “Unity Desktop” Are Working on a New Remix&lt;/a&gt; via Foss Mint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Grailville Wetlands</category><category>News</category><category>Ubuntu</category><guid>https://belkinsa.github.io/SenseOpenness/blog/and-we-are-back/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 17:51:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>